Guide to the Reginald Sellman negatives, 1911-1935
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Reginald Sellman negatives 1911-1935
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Sellman, Reginald, b. 1884.
1.5 Linear Feet 914 Items
Amateur photographer and physician from Baltimore, Maryland.
Collection consists of 898 nitrate negative images and two prints with images taken by amateur photographer Reginald Sellman from 1911 to 1935, chiefly in Baltimore, Maryland and environs. Subjects include Susie Ford, his wife Obedience (Bedie) Darden Sellman, and their son Bruce Darden Sellman; places featured include Baltimore buildings, streets, bridges, railway stations, monuments, parks, hospitals, and medical teaching institutions. Institutions include Johns Hopkins and the Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium, founded by Reginald Sellman's father, William A. B. Sellman. There are images of residences in or near Baltimore where Reginald and Susie Sellman lived. There are many snapshots of family members, and shots taken during hikes, camping trips, and visits to parks. Maryland locations include Baltimore County historic sites and parks: the Owing's Mills area, Gwynn's Falls, Chatalonee, Loch Raven, Druid Lake, the Chesapeake's Eastern Shore, Elk River, and the Patapsco River. The Sellmans often visited relatives in North Carolina; thus, there are also many images taken in early 20th century Beaufort, Goldsboro, La Grange, Kinston, and Raleigh. Some feature commercial fishing scenes and cotton transport. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research with some restrictions: Nitrate negatives can only be consulted with permission of the Curator of Documentary Arts.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Reginald Sellman photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2009.
Biographical Note
Reginald Oliver Sellman (b. 1884 Dec. 12) was the only son of Baltimore physician and gynecologist William Alfred Belt Sellman and his wife Mary Oliver Sellman. Reginald attended Johns Hopkins University and received a Bachelor's of Arts Degree there in 1908, and an M.D in 1912. Shortly after he was a resident physician at the Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium, and later was listed as a physician on Charles St. Susie Ford, who appears in many of the photos before 1914, is mentioned often as "my darling." Reginald took a next-to-last picture of her in 1914, and her gravesite (with no visible date) is also in the images. As her monument initials are "S.F.S.," Susie may have been married to Sellman and may have died in 1914. Sellman married Obedience "Bedie" Darden Sellman, who first appears in nursing school commencement photos, sometime after 1914, and they had a son, Bruce Darden Sellman, born in 1919. In 1942, at the age of 58, Sellman attempted to enlist in the U.S. Army. The date or place of his death is unknown.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of 898 nitrate negatives and two small prints with images taken by amateur photographer and Baltimore resident Reginald Sellman from 1911 to 1935. They were originally stored in four black cases, one of which has been retained for the collection, and they were meticulously indexed using handwritten cards. The images are arranged in original chronological order and listed by the photographer's original identification number has been retained; the titles were also taken from the original index cards. Note: Nitrate negatives can only be consulted with permission of the Curator of Documentary Arts.
The snapshots were chiefly taken in Baltimore, Maryland and Baltimore County, and depict buildings, streets, bridges, railway stations, parks, rivers, and monuments, and many family members, especially Reginald's friend (possibly a fianceé) Susie S. Ford, and later, his wife Obedience, and their son Bruce. There are quite a few photographs taken on day trips to historic sites and parks in Baltimore County such as St. Thomas Episcopal Church, Chattalonee, Gwynn Falls, Owings Mills, Massey, and Lake Roland. Sellman clearly enjoyed being outside; there are many images of activities such as camping, hiking, and visiting parks and Eastern Shore recreation areas.
Reginald's father, William A. B. Sellman, was a noted Baltimore gynecologist and founder of a sanatorium in Baltimore, thus there are views of hospitals (most views are labeled as "B.S.S.," almost certainly the Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium on Charles St.); a few interior shots of the "B.S.S." include an operating room. There are also exterior views of medical teaching institutions such as Johns Hopkins Hospital. In one of the two positive prints in the collection, Susie Ford is shown wearing a nurse's uniform.
There are images of apartment buildings and houses where Reginald and other family members lived, and some interior shots of rooms. There are many casual snapshots of family members. Later images depict Sellman's young son, Bruce, as a baby and a toddler, along with his mother, Obedience (Bedie) Darden Sellman (O.D.S.). She first appears in the images as Obedience Cox Darden, at her own commencement at a nursing school in May 1914.
Reginald and Obedience Sellman often visited her relatives in North Carolina; thus, there are many series of vacation photographs from the 1920s taken in Raleigh, Beaufort, Goldsboro, La Grange, and Kinston, N.C. Depicted are train stations, relatives' houses, railroads, street scenes, and businesses, some owned by relatives. A long series features scenes from the Methodist Orphanage in Raleigh, possibly where relatives worked. Zylpha or Zylphia Darden, a cousing of Bedie's, often appears with the baby Bruce. There are many scenes from Beaufort, N.C., with commercial fishing, streets, and the waterfront. Other earlier vacation spots Reginald visited with Susie depicted include the Eastern Shore, with Tollchester Beach and its amusement part and piers; Harper's Ferry, W. Va.; and the Blue Ridge, Va. area. The last images from 1935 feature Susie Ford's grave and monument in Mount View Cemetery (undentified state); she probably died in spring 1914.
Also in the collection are four sets of handwritten index cards listing each negative's identification number, roll of film and frame, caption, and technical details such as camera settings, exposure, film number, and date when image was developed. The cards are filed at the beginning of each group of negatives represented by the set. One original black storage case has also been retained, as well as advertisement and leaflets featuring photographic supplies, and an envelope of paper corner mounts. Apparently, Sellman also photographed with glass plates, but these are not present in the collection. There were also several places in the storage case where the film negatives were missing; these are noted in the finding aid.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Ford, Susie S.
Sellman, Bruce Darden, 1919-1954
Sellman, Obedience Darden
Sellman, Reginald Oliver, b. 1884
Sellman family (Md.)
Darden family (N.C.)
Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium (Baltimore, Md.)
Johns Hopkins Hospital
Physicians -- Baltimore (Md.)
Photography -- Maryland
Baltimore (Md.)--History
Baltimore (Md.)--Pictorial works
Baltimore County (Md.)--History
Baltimore County (Md.)--Pictorial works
Beaufort (N.C.)--Pictorial works
Eastern Shore (Md. and Va.)--Pictorial works
Goldsboro (N.C.)--Pictorial works
La Grange (N.C.)--Pictorial works
Kinston (N.C.)--Pictorial works
Raleigh (N.C.)--Pictorial works
Black-and-white photographs
Nitrate negatives
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
Contents of Collection
- Reginald Sellman negatives, 1911-1935, (3 boxes)
  A collection of 898 black-and-white nitrate negatives representing urban scenes in Baltimore, rural scenes in Maryland (particularly Baltimore County), snapshots of family members, and recreational areas around the Eastern Shore and the Chesapeake watershed, in Virginia and West Virginia, and in North Carolina towns where relatives of the Sellmans lived. Arranged in original chronological order. Titles, numerical identifiers, and dates are taken from Sellman's handwritten card indexes, also included in the collection, and most likely reflect the date the image was taken with the exception of some images dated from the 1930s. Sellman often used abbreviations for family members' names - most of these have been spelled out for the user.
  [Nitrate negatives can only be consulted with permission of the Curator of Documentary Arts.]
  - Index list and index cards, negatives 1-250 (Box 1)
  - Union Station from apartment windows, 1911 Dec. 27 (Box 1, Image 1)
  - Xmas tree in apartment, 1911 Dec. 27 (Box 1, Image 2)
  - Xmas tree from parlor door, 1911 Dec. 27 (Box 1, Image 3)
  - Mother and Susie on library sofa, 1911 Dec. 27 (Box 1, Image 4)
  - Mary on library sofa, 1911 Dec. 27 (Box 1, Image 5)
  - Susie and R.O.S. [Reginald Oliver Sellman) on library sofa, 1911 Dec. 27 (Box 1, Image 6)
  - Front steps of Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1911 Dec. 28 (Box 1, Image 7)
  - Anatomical building of J. H. Medical School, 1911 Dec. 28 (Box 1, Image 8)
  - Union Station from Hanging Gardens, 1911 Dec. 29 (Box 1, Image 9)
  - Key Monument on Eutaw Place, 1911 Dec. 29 (Box 1, Image 10)
  - Looking north on Eutaw Place, 1911 Dec. 29 (Box 1, Image 11)
  - Sanatorium from South East, 1912 Jan. 1 (Box 1, Image 12)
  - Sanatorium from East, 1912 Jan. 1 (Box 1, Image 13)
  - Xmas tree from library door, 1912 Jan. 4 (Box 1, Image 14)
  - Union Station in snow from apartments, 1912 Jan. 7 (Box 1, Image 15)
  - Looking north from apartment in snow, 1912 Jan. 7 (Box 1, Image 16)
  - Susie on library sofa, 1912 Jan. 7 (Box 1, Image 17)
  - Jones Falls from bridge at Mt. Washington, 1912 Jan. 21 (Box 1, Image 18)
  - East on Elmwood Avenue just west of Edgewood Road in Roland Park, 1912 Jan. 21 (Box 1, Image 19)
  - North East from Federal Hill, 1912 Jan. 23 (Box 1, Image 20)
  - North from Federal Hill, 1912 Jan. 23 (Box 1, Image 21)
  - South East from Federal Hill, 1912 Jan. 23 (Box 1, Image 22)
  - Homewood Apartments, Nicholas Street, 1912 Jan. 25 (Box 1, Image 23)
  - Carrol Mansion, Homewood, 1912 Jan. 25 (Box 1, Image 24)
  - Southeast from North Avenue bridge, 1912 Mar. 17 (Box 1, Image 25)
  - Northeast from Druid Lake, 1912 Mar. 17 (Box 1, Image 26)
  - Southeast from Druid Lake, 1912 Mar. 17 (Box 1, Image 27)
  - Chattalonee Hotel from S. of [Richmond?], 1912 Mar. 31 (Box 1, Image 28)
    Chattalonee, Baltimore County, Maryland, was both an African American postbellum settlement and a resort community. The hotel was built in the 1890s and razed in the 1920s. The area was known for its springs.
  - Big Spring at Chattalonee, Sue, 1912 Mar. 31 (Box 1, Image 29)
  - Back of Chattalonee Hotel from west, 1912 Mar. 31 (Box 1, Image 30)
  - "Our Cottage" at Chattalonee (?), Sue, 1912 Mar. 31 (Box 1, Image 31)
  - Cave property from St. Thomas' Church, 1912 Mar. 31 (Box 1, Image 32)
  - St. Thomas' Church from west (front of church), 1912 Mar. 31 (Box 1, Image 33)
  - Sanatorium from southeast, 1912 Apr. 5 (Box 1, Image 34)
  - South of Eccleston, looking north, 1912 Apr. 6 (Box 1, Image 35)
  - Just south of Eccleston, looking north, 1912 Apr. 6 (Box 1, Image 36)
  - Stream just north of Eccleston, looking east, 1912 Apr. 6 (Box 1, Image 37)
  - Chattalonee from bottom of hill, 1912 Apr. 6 (Box 1, Image 38)
  - Ponds at Chattalonee, 1912 Apr. 6 (Box 1, Image 39)
  - Green Spring Road at Slaughterhouse Run, 1912 Apr. 9 (Box 1, Image 40)
  - Spring just above no. 40, 1912 Apr. 9 (Box 1, Image 41)
  - Just west of Brooklandville, 1912 Apr. 9 (Box 1, Image 42)
  - Just N. of Rockland, looking East, 1912 Apr. 9 (Box 1, Image 43)
  - Stream between Rockland and Sorento, 1912 Apr. 9 (Box 1, Image 44)
  - Stream north of Sorento, 1912 Apr. 9 (Box 1, Image 45)
  - Falls at Lake Roland, 1912 Apr. 10 (Box 1, Image 46)
  - Caves property, looking north, 1912 Apr. 10 (Box 1, Image 47)
  - St. Thomas' Church from south (side of church), 1912 Apr. 10 (Box 1, Image 48)
  - Boat Lake, Druid Hill Park, from west, 1912 Apr. 24 (Box 1, Image 49)
  - Gwynn's Falls Park, looking south, below Windsor Road, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 50)
  - Below bridge over Gwynn's Falls, in park, looking south, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 51)
  - Path in Gwynn's Falls Park, above ravine, looking north, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 52)
  - Ravine in Gwynn's Falls Park, looking east, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 53)
  - Railroad bridge over Gwynn's Falls Park, looking south, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 54)
  - Looking north from Railroad bridge, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 55)
  - Edmonson Avenue bridge from north, looking south, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 56)
  - Edmonson Avenue bridge from north, looking southeast, 1912 Apr. 25 (Box 1, Image 57)
  - Stream in ravine, Gwynn's Falls Park, 1912 Apr. 26 (Box 1, Image 58)
  - Stream in ravine, Gwynn's Falls Park, 1912 Apr. 26 (Box 1, Image 59)
  - Caves property from St. Thomas' Church, 1912 Apr. 28 (Box 1, Image 60)
  - Apple orchard just north of St. Thomas' Church, 1912 Apr. 28 (Box 1, Image 61)
  - Johnstone's Square from northwest, 1912 May 1 (Box 1, Image 62)
  - Madison Square from northwest, 1912 May 1 (Box 1, Image 63)
  - Reginald Sellman in ravine, Gwynn's Falls Park, 1912 May 1 (Box 1, Image 64)
  - Dead Run, east of Franklin, 1912 May 1 (Box 1, Image 65)
  - Franklin, looking east, 1912 May 1 (Box 1, Image 66)
    Dead Run is in the Gwynn Falls park area.
  - Windsor Hill Road bridge at [Pels?], from west, 1912 May 1 (Box 1, Image 67)
  - East along Hill Road, above Dickeyville, 1912 May 3 (Box 1, Image 68)
  - West along Gwynn's Falls above Dickeyville, 1912 May 3 (Box 1, Image 69)
  - Electric car bridge at Gwynn Oak, 1912 May 3 (Box 1, Image 70)
  - Falls of Gwynn's Falls above Woodlawn, 1912 May 3 (Box 1, Image 71)
  - Northwest from hill by Gwynn's Falls above Dickeyville, 1912 May 4 (Box 1, Image 72)
  - East on Windsor Road, just east of Loraine Cemetery, 1912 May 4 (Box 1, Image 73)
  - Northwest on Westminster Pike, just southwest of Glenn Falls, 1912 May 5 (Box 1, Image 74)
  - Patapsco River, south of Glenn Falls, 1912 May 5 (Box 1, Image 75)
  - North along Patapsco, just south of Keyser Run, 1912 May 5 (Box 1, Image 76)
  - West to junction of Patapsco and Beaver Run, 1912 May 5 (Box 1, Image 77)
  - Monument Square from Centre Street, 1912 May 10 (Box 1, Image 78)
  - South on Dead Man from bridge at Loraine Cemetery, 1912 May 10 (Box 1, Image 79)
  - North of Gwynn's Falls from bridge at Lochearn, 1912 May 10 (Box 1, Image 80)
  - Desk in my room at H. T. [or Mt.?] Royal, 1912 May 13 (Box 1, Image 81)
  - Reginald Sellman full face, taken by self, 1912 May 17 (Box 1, Image 82)
  - Reginald Sellman half face, taken by self, 1912 May 17 (Box 1, Image 83)
  - South to bridge at Lochearn, 1912 May 18 (Box 1, Image 84)
  - Up Gwynn's Falls above Lochearn, 1912 May 18 (Box 1, Image 85)
  - Bridge several miles above Lochearn, 1912 May 18 (Box 1, Image 86)
  - South on Gwynn's Falls several miles above Lochearn, 1912 May 18 (Box 1, Image 87)
  - North of Gwynn's Falls about a mile from Old Court Road, 1912 May 18 (Box 1, Image 88)
  - East of Gwynn's Falls at Old Court Road, 1912 May 18 (Box 1, Image 89)
  - Western Maryland train between Roslyn and Sandhook, 1912 May 19 (Box 1, Image 90)
  - Northeast from Elliott City, 1912 May 19 (Box 1, Image 91)
  - North along B. and O. [Baltimore and Ohio] below Union Dam in Patapsco, 1912 May 19 (Box 1, Image 92)
  - Union Dam, Patapsco from west bank, 1912 May 19 (Box 1, Image 93)
  - North on B. and O. above Union Dam, 1912 May 19 (Box 1, Image 94)
  - Northwest on Patapsco above Hallofield, 1912 May 19 (Box 1, Image 95)
  - South through Dorsey Tunnel, 1912 May 19 (Box 1, Image 96)
  - Northeast on Lake Roland, from W. shore, above Hollins, 1912 May 24 (Box 1, Image 97)
  - Northeast from E. of [Towson?], near Joppa Road, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 98)
  - Lower part of Limekiln Hollow, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 99)
  - Kilns in Limekiln Hollow, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 100)
  - Lower part of Loch Raven, below falls, lunch [here?], 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 101)
  - Falls at Loch Raven, from below, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 102)
  - Falls at Loch Raven, from side, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 103)
  - Looking up Loch Raven, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 104)
  - Looking down Loch Raven, below Meredith Bridge, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 105)
  - North in Dulaney Valley from below Meredith Bridge, 1912 May 26 (Box 1, Image 106)
  - St. Thomas' Church Lane, looking west, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 107)
  - St. Thomas' Church, from south, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 108)
  - Entrance to Caves property, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 109)
  - Bridge at North Run along Caves' Road, looking west, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 110)
  - In woods above North Run, lunch here, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 111)
  - North from Falls Road and "Broadway," B. M. 616, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 112)
  - South of Falls, from below, B. M. 616, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 113)
  - Brooklandville Station, from north, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 114)
  - Railroad between Rockland and Sorento, looking south, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 115)
  - Lake Roland off onto lakeside, 1912 June 2 (Box 1, Image 116)
  - West on Liberty W. of West Archington, 1912 June 9 (Box 1, Image 117)
  - South along Gwynn's Falls above Lochearn (and I9), 1912 June 9 (Box 1, Image 118)
  - Gwynn's Falls above Lochearn at first bridge (and I10), 1912 June 9 (Box 1, Image 119)
  - Stream just about M3, 1912 June 9 (Box 1, Image 120)
  - North on Gwynn's Falls above first bridge above Lochearn, 1912 June 9 (Box 1, Image 121)
  - Field by Gwynn's Falls at second bridge above Lochearn, 1912 June 9 (Box 1, Image 122)
  - North on Baltimore Harbor, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 123)
  - Fort McHenry just east (on [Steamer?] Louise), 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 124)
  - Shelton from west, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 125)
  - C. D. Reid on St. Louise, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 126)
  - Tolchester [whip?] from St. Louise, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 127)
    The Louise was a passenger steamer that ran from Baltimore's inner city to several locations, including Tolchester Beach, Kent County, a popular Chesapeake Bay resort area and amusement park.
  - Tolchester beach from south, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 128)
  - Susie on bridge in Tolchester, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 129)
  - [Steamer?] Louise arriving in Tolchester in afternoon, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 130)
  - Pony and monkey circus in Tolchester, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 131)
  - Down by from main building in Tolchester, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 132)
  - St. John's cadets in camp at Tolchester, 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 133)
  - St. John's cadets in camp at Tolchester (marching), 1912 June 10 (Box 1, Image 134)
  - R.O.S., M.D., in front of City College, 1912 June 11 (Box 1, Image 135)
  - R.O.S., M.D., in front of City College, 1912 June 11 (Box 1, Image 136)
  - St. Susquehanna from pier at Bayshore, 1912 June 22 (Box 1, Image 137)
  - Pier at Bayshore, 1912 June 22 (Box 1, Image 138)
  - Blue Ridge above Thurmond (from train), 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 139)
  - Mountain [view?] below Deerfield (from train), 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 140)
  - Cumberland Valley from Pen Mar, looking north, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 141)
    Pen Mar Park was a scenic spot near the Mason-Dixon line. It featured a popular amusement park that was taken down in the 1940s.
  - Toward Buena Vista from Pen Mar, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 142)
  - Our neighbors and lunch, Pen Mar, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 143)
  - Toward Blue Mountain [Home?] from High Rock, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 144)
  - West from High Rock, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 145)
  - Cumberland Valley from High Rock, looking north, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 146)
  - Susie on path to [Quinmark?], 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 147)
  - S. from top of [Quinmark], 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 148)
  - S.E. from top of [Quinmark], 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 149)
  - Susie at High Rock, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 150)
  - R.O.S. at High Rock, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 151)
  - High Rock from west, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 152)
  - Blue Mountain Express at Pen Mar, 1912 June 23 (Box 1, Image 153)
  - U.S.S. Kansas from Fort McHenry, 1912 June 24 (Box 1, Image 154)
  - U.S.S. Louisiana from Fort McHenry, 1912 June 24 (Box 1, Image 155)
  - Down river from Fort McHenry, 1912 June 24 (Box 1, Image 156)
  - U.S.S. Louisiana from St. Cambridge, 1912 June 26 (Box 1, Image 157)
  - Pier at Clairbourne from St. Cambridge, 1912 June 26 (Box 1, Image 158)
  - Convention Hall from Bolton and Hoffman Streets, 1912 June 30 (Box 1, Image 159)
  - Collier Orion from [Steamer?] Emma Giles, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Image 160)
    The USS Orion, was commissioned in late July 1912 as one of several large colliers intended to refuel the Navy's coal-burning warships.
  - Naval Academy at Annapolis from [Steamer?] Emma Giles, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Image 161)
  - Annapolis from wharf, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Image 162)
  - Galesville Wharf, West River, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Image 163)
  - Chalk Point Wharf, West River, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Image 164)
  - South River, just above Drumsbridge, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Image 165)
  - Contee's Wharf, South River, 1912 July 1 (Box 1, Image 166)
  - Susie on {Steamer?] Dreamland, 1912 July 3 (Box 1, Image 167)
  - Ox cart at Chesapeake Beach, 1912 July 3 (Box 1, Image 168)
  - [Steamer?] Dreamland at Chesapeake Beach, 1912 July 3 (Box 1, Image 169)
  - Boat just off Chesapeake Beach, 1912 July 3 (Box 1, Image 170)
  - Stream at Lakeside, 1912 Aug. (Box 1, Image 171)
  - Stream at Lakeside, 1912 Aug. (Box 1, Image 172)
  - Susie at fence in Lakeside, 1912 Aug. (Box 1, Image 173)
  - Mrs. Long's home, Roland Park, 1912 Oct. (Box 1, Image 174)
  - Long's children, home in Roland Park, 1912 (Box 1, Image 175)
  - Third floor corridor from west window, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 176)
  - M[innie] [or Mamie?] at [instrument?] care, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 177)
  - M[innie] and Mr. Weiskettle, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium] #114, 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 178)
  - M[innie] and Mr. Weiskettle, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium] #114, 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 179)
  - M[innie] and Mr. Weiskettle, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], no.114, 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 180)
  - M[innie] and Tommy on bed in pink room, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 181)
  - M[innie], Slatey and Tommy on porch of pink room, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 182)
  - M[innie], Slatey and Tommy on porch of pink room, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 183)
  - M[innie] and Tommy by the mantle in the pink room, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 184)
  - M[innie] in sun parlor, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 185)
  - M[innie] and Slatey in sun parlor, B.S.S. [Bielder-Sellman Sanatorium], 1912 Nov. (Box 1, Image 186)